(404) 729-1080

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Front & Back End Development | Application Programming Interfaces | Software Development Lifecycle

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Full Stack Web Developer with background in Computer engineering technology; brings robust IT experience in programming, front-end web design, back-end databases, network engineering, telecom, technical troubleshooting, customer service and support. Experience ranges from building retail and non-profit websites, to engineering, voice and data networks for AT&T.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Portfolio: https://jefferycarmichael.github.io/Portfolio/ Github: https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Bootstrap	HTML	CSS	JavaScript	jQuery
Ajax	React	JSX	ES6	Nodejs
MongoDB	MySQL	Firebase	MERN Stack	Angular
Git Version Control	Adobe Photoshop			

PROJECTS

Catawba Coffee

https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael/Project_3 | https://catawba.herokuapp.com/

- This project is a proposed design for a web site for our client, Catawba Coffee Co.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6, JSX, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, React, Axios, Sendgrid, Git and Webpack

SNIPPETS

https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael/Snippets-.git | https://pacific-everglades-43020.herokuapp.com

- Snippets is an application that gives users a place to post and share short pieces of cool code("snippets")
 online.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, Git, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Express-Handlebars, MySql, Passport, Sequelize and Sessions.

E/Z Travel

https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael/travel-site | https://github.com/JefferyCarmichael/travel-site

- **E/Z Travel** is a web site that can used to look-up flight information.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Materialize and Git

EDUCATION

2018 Full Stack Web Development Certificate, University of North Carolina at Charlotte A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, Git & ReactJS.

B.S., Computer & Electrical Engineering Technology, Southern Polytechnic State University, Marietta GA

JEFFERY CARMICHAEL Page 2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CODE for AMERICA, Charlotte, NC

2019-Present

Web Developer

- Developing a customizable application that provides formerly incarcerated people with a reentry roadmap to assist them as they work to rebuild their lives and reintegrate into their communities.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, ES6, JSX, Git, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, React, MongoDB, Webpack

MACY'S, Clearwater, FL

2008 - 2017

Credit Services Analyst

- Selected by IT manager for special project above responsibilities to install 1200 IP phones in the call center
- Consistently received numerous "outstanding" ratings in customer surveys when resolving customer issues

COMCAST, Alpharetta, GA

2007 - 2008

High Speed Internet Specialist

- Provided technical support for high speed internet and video service in a high-volume call center environment
- Consistently achieved accuracy ratings over 95% for assessing technician deployment; saved company time and money on unnecessary technician calls
- Handled 60+ calls per day

PHOENIX STAIRS, Canton, GA

2005 - 2007

Estimator / Technical Support

- Efficiently and effectively researched and resolved technical problems for internal users
- Accurately evaluated project scope and developed estimates to create detailed work orders

ADEX CORPORATION, Alpharetta, GA

2004 - 2005

Network Engineer

- Provided detailed engineering of voice and data network projects for customers including AT&T and Bell South
- Selected for a cross-company team organized to improve delivery of engineering specifications
- Member of core transition team to migrate engineering services and systems from Lucent to Adex

VOLUNTEER & COMMUNITY

CODE for CHARLOTTE, Charlotte, NC

2018 – present

Web Developer

- Assists in planning of civic technology projects for the local community

WORLD OUTREACH MINISTRIES, St. Petersburg, FL

2015 - 2018

Website Administrator

- Maintained global website; Managed website transition to WordPress; Recorded, edited and uploaded weekly podcasts
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop and WordPress